[
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the charm that creates a shield?",
        "answer": "Protego",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 9209,
                "passage": "screamed Mrs. Weasley. Bellatrix laughed, the same exhilarated laugh her cousin Sirius had given as he toppled backward through the veil, and suddenly Harry knew what was going to happen before it did. Molly's curse soared beneath Bellatrix's outstretched arm and hit her squarely in the chest, directly over her heart. Bellatrix's gloating smile froze, her eyes seemed to bulge: For the tiniest space of time she knew what had happened, and then she toppled, and the watching crowd roared, and Voldemort screamed. Harry felt as though he turned in slow motion; he saw McGonagall, Kingsley, and Slughorn blasted backward, flailing and writhing through the air, as Voldemort's fury at the fall of his last, best lieutenant exploded with the force of a bomb. Voldemort raised his wand and directed it at Molly Weasley. \"Protego!\" roared Harry, and the Shield Charm expanded in the middle of the Hall, and Voldemort stared around for the source as Harry pulled off the Invisibility Cloak at last. The yell of shock, the cheers, the screams on every side of \"Harry!\" \"HE'S ALIVE!\" were stifled at once. The crowd was afraid, and silence fell abruptly and completely as Voldemort and Harry looked at each other, and began, at the same moment, to circle each other. \"I don't want anyone else to try to help,\" Harry said loudly, and in the total silence his voice carried like a trumpet call."
            }
        ],
        "id": 395
    },
    {
        "question": "Later in the series, we learn that one character's patronus is a doe. How does this subtle detail connect back to earlier hints in the books, and what does it reveal about his personal history?",
        "answer": "Severus Snape's Patronus is a doe—the same as Lily Potter's—which reveals his lifelong, unspoken love for her.",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 9218,
                "passage": "And you never realized it, because of the thing you can't understand. You never saw Snape cast a Patronus, did you, Riddle?\" Voldemort did not answer. They continued to circle each other like wolves about to tear each other apart. \"Snape's Patronus was a doe,\" said Harry, \"the same as my mother's, because he loved her for nearly all of his life, from the time when they were children. You should have realized,\" he said as he saw Voldemort's nostrils flare, \"he asked you to spare her life, didn't he?\""
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 9098,
                "passage": "Dumbledore watched her fly away, and as her silvery glow faded he turned back to Snape, and his eyes were full of tears. \"After all this time?\" \"Always,\" said Snape. And the scene shifted. Now, Harry saw Snape talking to the portrait of Dumbledore behind his desk. \"You will have to give Voldemort the correct date of Harry's departure from his aunt and uncle's,\" said Dumbledore. \"Not to do so will raise suspicion, when Voldemort believes you so well informed. However, you must plant the idea of decoys; that, I think, ought to ensure Harry's safety. Try Confunding Mundungus Fletcher. And Severus, if you are forced to take part in the chase, be sure to act your part convincingly."
            }
        ],
        "id": 614
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that makes objects grow hair?",
        "answer": "No such spell in book",
        "list of reference": [],
        "id": 241
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Weasley twins' joke shop?",
        "answer": "Weasleys' Wizard Wheezes",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": "Harry and Ron edged out of the kitchen, and they, Hermione, and Ginny set off along the narrow hallway and up the rickety staircase that zigzagged through the house to the upper stories. \"What are Weasleys' Wizard Wheezes?\" Harry asked as they climbed. Ron and Ginny both laughed, although Hermione didn't. \"Mum found this stack of order forms when she was cleaning Fred and George's room,\" said Ron quietly. \"Great long price lists for stuff they've invented. Joke stuff, you know. Fake wands and trick sweets, loads of stuff. It was brilliant, I never knew they'd been inventing all that ...\"\n\"We've been hearing explosions out of their room for ages, but we never thought they were actually making things,\" said Ginny. \"We thought they just liked the noise.\"",
                "passage": "Reference id Harry and Ron edged out of the kitchen, and they, Hermione, and Ginny set off along the narrow hallway and up the rickety staircase that zigzagged through the house to the upper stories. \"What are Weasleys' Wizard Wheezes?\" Harry asked as they climbed. Ron and Ginny both laughed, although Hermione didn't. \"Mum found this stack of order forms when she was cleaning Fred and George's room,\" said Ron quietly. \"Great long price lists for stuff they've invented. Joke stuff, you know. Fake wands and trick sweets, loads of stuff. It was brilliant, I never knew they'd been inventing all that ...\"\n\"We've been hearing explosions out of their room for ages, but we never thought they were actually making things,\" said Ginny. \"We thought they just liked the noise.\" not found"
            }
        ],
        "id": 338
    },
    {
        "question": "Who becomes the Gryffindor Quidditch captain after Oliver Wood?",
        "answer": "Angelina Johnson",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 4656,
                "passage": "\"What?\" said both Harry and Ron together. \"Well ... maybe he didn't want to draw attention to Hagrid not being here.\" \"What d'you mean, draw attention to it?\" said Ron, half laughing. \"How could we not notice?\" Before Hermione could answer, a tall black girl with long, braided hair had marched up to Harry. \"Hi, Angelina.\" \"Hi,\" she said briskly, \"good summer?\""
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 4657,
                "passage": "And without waiting for an answer, \"Listen, I've been made Gryffindor Quidditch Captain.\" \"Nice one,\" said Harry, grinning at her; he suspected Angelina's pep talks might not be as long-winded as Oliver Wood's had been, which could only be an improvement. \"Yeah, well, we need a new Keeper now Oliver's left. Tryouts are on Friday at five o'clock and I want the whole team there, all right? Then we can see how the new person'll fit in.\" \"Okay,\" said Harry, and she smiled at him and departed. \"I'd forgotten Wood had left,\" said Hermione vaguely, sitting down beside Ron and pulling a plate of toast toward her. \"I suppose that will make quite a difference to the team?\" \"I s'pose,\" said Harry, taking the bench opposite."
            }
        ],
        "id": 405
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the ghost of Ravenclaw Tower?",
        "answer": "The Grey Lady",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 8929,
                "passage": "\"Harry! My dear boy!\" Nick made to grasp Harry's hands with both of his own: Harry's felt as though they had been thrust into icy water. \"Nick, you've got to help me. Who's the ghost of Ravenclaw Tower?\" Nearly Headless Nick looked surprised and a little offended. \"The Gray Lady, of course; but if it is ghostly services you require - ?\""
            }
        ],
        "id": 333
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Ravenclaw boy who loves astronomy?",
        "answer": "Roger Davies",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": "B",
                "passage": "Reference id B not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "o",
                "passage": "Reference id o not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "o",
                "passage": "Reference id o not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "k",
                "passage": "Reference id k not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": " ",
                "passage": "Reference id   not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "4",
                "passage": "Reference id 4 not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": ",",
                "passage": "Reference id , not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": " ",
                "passage": "Reference id   not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "C",
                "passage": "Reference id C not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "h",
                "passage": "Reference id h not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "a",
                "passage": "Reference id a not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "p",
                "passage": "Reference id p not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "t",
                "passage": "Reference id t not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "e",
                "passage": "Reference id e not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "r",
                "passage": "Reference id r not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": " ",
                "passage": "Reference id   not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "2",
                "passage": "Reference id 2 not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "3",
                "passage": "Reference id 3 not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": ",",
                "passage": "Reference id , not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": " ",
                "passage": "Reference id   not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "P",
                "passage": "Reference id P not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "a",
                "passage": "Reference id a not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "r",
                "passage": "Reference id r not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "a",
                "passage": "Reference id a not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "g",
                "passage": "Reference id g not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "r",
                "passage": "Reference id r not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "a",
                "passage": "Reference id a not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "p",
                "passage": "Reference id p not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "h",
                "passage": "Reference id h not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": " ",
                "passage": "Reference id   not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "5",
                "passage": "Reference id 5 not found"
            }
        ],
        "id": 249
    },
    {
        "question": "Which book does Dumbledore leave to Hermione in his will?",
        "answer": "He leaves her The Tales of Beedle the Bard.",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 7845,
                "passage": "\"What else could I do with it?\" Evidently Scrimgeour had no suggestions. After squinting at Ron for a moment or two, he turned back to Dumbledore's will.\n\" 'To Miss Hermione Jean Granger, I leave my copy of The Tales of Beedle the Bard, in the hope that she will find it entertaining and instructive.' \"\nScrimgeour now pulled out of the bag a small book that looked as ancient as the copy of Secrets of the Darkest Art upstairs. Its binding was stained and peeling in places."
            }
        ],
        "id": 25
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the headmaster before Dumbledore?",
        "answer": "Armando Dippet",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 1247,
                "passage": "But this was a lie. In my fifth year, the Chamber was opened and the monster attacked several students, finally killing one. I caught the person who'd opened the Chamber and he was expelled. But the headmaster, Professor Dippet, ashamed that such a thing had happened at Hogwarts, forbade me to tell the truth. A story was given out that the girl had died in a freak accident. They gave me a nice, shiny, engraved trophy for my trouble and warned me to keep my mouth shut."
            }
        ],
        "id": 184
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the magical plant that strangles people?",
        "answer": "Devil's Snare",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 643,
                "passage": "Hermione had managed to free herself before the plant got a firm grip on her. Now she watched in horror as the two boys fought to pull the plant off them, but the more they strained against it, the tighter and faster the plant wound around them. \"Stop moving!\" Hermione ordered them. \"I know what this is - it's Devil's Snare!\" \"Oh, I'm so glad we know what it's called, that's a great help,\" snarled Ron, leaning back, trying to stop the plant from curling around his neck."
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 644,
                "passage": "\"Shut up, I'm trying to remember how to kill it!\" said Hermione. \"Well, hurry up, I can't breathe!\" Harry gasped, wrestling with it as it curled around his chest. \"Devil's Snare, Devil's Snare ... what did Professor Sprout say? - it likes the dark and the damp -\"\n\"So light a fire!\" Harry choked. \"Yes - of course - but there's no wood!\" Hermione cried, wringing her hands. \"HAVE YOU GONE MAD?\""
            }
        ],
        "id": 223
    },
    {
        "question": "What creature does Lupin teach the students to repel in Defense Against the Dark Arts?",
        "answer": "Boggart",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 1765,
                "passage": "Professor Lupin had raised his eyebrows. \"I was hoping that Neville would assist me with the first stage of the operation,\" he said, \"and I am sure he will perform it admirably.\" Neville's face went, if possible, even redder. Snape's lip curled, but he left, shutting the door with a snap. \"Now, then,\" said Professor Lupin, beckoning the class toward the end of the room, where there was nothing but an old wardrobe where the teachers kept their spare robes. As Professor Lupin went to stand next to it, the wardrobe gave a sudden wobble, banging off the wall. \"Nothing to worry about,\" said Professor Lupin calmly because a few people had jumped backward in alarm. \"There's a boggart in there.\" Most people seemed to feel that this was something to worry about. Neville gave Professor Lupin a look of pure terror, and Seamus Finnigan eyed the now rattling doorknob apprehensively. \"Boggarts like dark, enclosed spaces,\" said Professor Lupin. \"Wardrobes, the gap beneath beds, the cupboards under sinks - I've even met one that had lodged itself in a grandfather clock. This one moved in yesterday afternoon, and I asked the headmaster if the staff would leave it to give my third years some practice. \"So, the first question we must ask ourselves is, what is a boggart?\" Hermione put up her hand. \"It's a shape-shifter,\" she said."
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 1766,
                "passage": "\"It can take the shape of whatever it thinks will frighten us most.\" \"Couldn't have put it better myself,\" said Professor Lupin, and Hermione glowed. \"So the boggart sitting in the darkness within has not yet assumed a form. He does not yet know what will frighten the person on the other side of the door. Nobody knows what a boggart looks like when he is alone, but when I let him out, he will immediately become whatever each of us most fears. \"This means,\" said Professor Lupin, choosing to ignore Neville's small sputter of terror, \"that we have a huge advantage over the boggart before we begin. Have you spotted it, Harry?\" Trying to answer a question with Hermione next to him, bobbing up and down on the balls of her feet with her hand in the air, was very off-putting, but Harry had a go. \"Er - because there are so many of us, it won't know what shape it should be?\" \"Precisely,\" said Professor Lupin, and Hermione put her hand down, looking a little disappointed."
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 1767,
                "passage": "\"It's always best to have company when you're dealing with a boggart. He becomes confused. Which should he become, a headless corpse or a flesh-eating slug? I once saw a boggart make that very mistake - tried to frighten two people at once and turned himself into half a slug. Not remotely frightening. \"The charm that repels a boggart is simple, yet it requires force of mind. You see, the thing that really finishes a boggart is laughter. What you need to do is force it to assume a shape that you find amusing."
            }
        ],
        "id": 318
    },
    {
        "question": "What specific phrase in a prophecy-like warning hints at a traitor's identity?",
        "answer": "The servant returns' points to Pettigrew.",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 2473,
                "passage": "said Dumbledore. \"Er - stranger than usual, you mean?\" \"Yes ... her voice went all deep and her eyes rolled and she said ... she said Voldemort's servant was going to set out to return to him before midnight. ... She said the servant would help him come back to power.\" Harry stared up at Dumbledore. \"And then she sort of became normal again, and she couldn't remember anything she'd said. Was it - was she making a real prediction? Dumbledore looked mildly impressed. \"Do you know, Harry, I think she might have been,\" he said thoughtfully. \"Who'd have thought it? That brings her total of real predictions up to two. I should offer her a pay raise. ...\"\n\"But -\" Harry looked at him, aghast. How could Dumbledore take this so calmly? \"But - I stopped Sirius and Professor Lupin from killing Pettigrew! That makes it my fault if Voldemort comes back!\""
            }
        ],
        "id": 520
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the magical creature that lives in fire?",
        "answer": "Salamander",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 1000,
                "passage": "The firelight glowed over the countless squashy armchairs where people sat reading, talking, doing homework or, in the case of Fred and George Weasley, trying to find out what would happen if you fed a Filibuster firework to a salamander. Fred had \"rescued\" the brilliant orange, fire-dwelling lizard from a Care of Magical Creatures class and it was now smoldering gently on a table surrounded by a knot of curious people. Harry was at the point of telling Ron and Hermione about Filch and the Kwikspell course when the salamander suddenly whizzed into the air, emitting loud sparks and bangs as it whirled wildly round the room. The sight of Percy bellowing himself hoarse at Fred and George, the spectacular display of tangerine stars showering from the salamander's mouth, and its escape into the fire, with accompanying explosions, drove both Filch and the Kwikspell envelope from Harry's mind. By the time Halloween arrived, Harry was regretting his rash promise to go to the deathday party. The rest of the school was happily anticipating their Halloween feast; the Great Hall had been decorated with the usual live bats, Hagrid's vast pumpkins had been carved into lanterns large enough for three men to sit in, and there were rumors that Dumbledore had booked a troupe of dancing skeletons for the entertainment. \"A promise is a promise,\" Hermione reminded Harry bossily. \"You said you'd go to the deathday party.\" So at seven o'clock, Harry, Ron, and Hermione walked straight past the doorway to the packed Great Hall, which was glittering invitingly with gold plates and candles, and directed their steps instead toward the dungeons. The passageway leading to Nearly Headless Nick's party had been lined with candles, too, though the effect was far from cheerful: These were long, thin, jet-black tapers, all burning bright blue, casting a dim, ghostly light even over their own living faces. The temperature dropped with every step they took. As Harry shivered and drew his robes tightly around him, he heard what sounded like a thousand fingernails scraping an enormous blackboard."
            }
        ],
        "id": 237
    },
    {
        "question": "What object does Ron inherit from Dumbledore?",
        "answer": "A Deluminator",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 7844,
                "passage": "Yes, here we are. ... 'To Ronald Bilius Weasley, I leave my Deluminator, in the hope that he will remember me when he uses it.' \"\nScrimgeour took from the bag an object that Harry had seen before: It looked something like a silver cigarette lighter, but it had, he knew, the power to suck all light from a place, and restore it, with a simple click. Scrimgeour leaned forward and passed the Deluminator to Ron, who took it and turned it over in his fingers, looking stunned. \"That is a valuable object,\" said Scrimgeour, watching Ron. \"It may even be unique. Certainly it is of Dumbledore's own design. Why would he have left you an item so rare?\" Ron shook his head, looking bewildered. \"Dumbledore must have taught thousands of students,\" Scrimgeour persevered. \"Yet the only ones he remembered in his will are you three. Why is that? To what use did he think you would put his Deluminator, Mr. Weasley?\" \"Put out lights, I s'pose,\" mumbled Ron."
            }
        ],
        "id": 153
    },
    {
        "question": "What plant traps Harry, Ron, and Hermione in the first book?",
        "answer": "Devil's Snare",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 643,
                "passage": "Hermione had managed to free herself before the plant got a firm grip on her. Now she watched in horror as the two boys fought to pull the plant off them, but the more they strained against it, the tighter and faster the plant wound around them. \"Stop moving!\" Hermione ordered them. \"I know what this is - it's Devil's Snare!\" \"Oh, I'm so glad we know what it's called, that's a great help,\" snarled Ron, leaning back, trying to stop the plant from curling around his neck."
            }
        ],
        "id": 116
    },
    {
        "question": "What creature does Hagrid keep in his hut as a baby in the first book?",
        "answer": "Norbert the dragon",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 527,
                "passage": "He was humming merrily as he stoked the fire. So now they had something else to worry about: what might happen to Hagrid if anyone found out he was hiding an illegal dragon in his hut. \"Wonder what it's like to have a peaceful life,\" Ron sighed, as evening after evening they struggled through all the extra homework they were getting. Hermione had now started making study schedules for Harry and Ron, too. It was driving them nuts. Then, one breakfast time, Hedwig brought Harry another note from Hagrid. He had written only two words: It's hatching. Ron wanted to skip Herbology and go straight down to the hut. Hermione wouldn't hear of it. \"Hermione, how many times in our lives are we going to see a dragon hatching?\""
            }
        ],
        "id": 120
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Hufflepuff seeker in Harry's fourth year?",
        "answer": "Cedric Diggory",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 1878,
                "passage": "\"We didn't - lose?\" \"Diggory got the Snitch,\" said George. \"Just after you fell. He didn't realize what had happened. When he looked back and saw you on the ground, he tried to call it off. Wanted a rematch. But they won fair and square ... even Wood admits it.\" \"Where is Wood?\" said Harry, suddenly realizing he wasn't there."
            }
        ],
        "id": 186
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Gryffindor girl who loves cats?",
        "answer": "Hermione Granger",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 1624,
                "passage": "Harry had no chance to speak to Ron or Hermione in the chaos of leaving; they were too busy heaving all their trunks down the Leaky Cauldron's narrow staircase and piling them up near the door, with Hedwig and Hermes, Percy's screech owl, perched on top in their cages. A small wickerwork basket stood beside the heap of trunks, spitting loudly. \"It's all right, Crookshanks,\" Hermione cooed through the wickerwork. \"I'll let you out on the train.\" \"You won't,\" snapped Ron. \"What about poor Scabbers, eh?\" He pointed at his chest, where a large lump indicated that Scabbers was curled up in his pocket. Mr. Weasley, who had been outside waiting for the Ministry cars, stuck his head inside. \"They're here,\" he said. \"Harry, come on.\" Mr. Weasley marched Harry across the short stretch of pavement toward the first of two old-fashioned dark green cars, each of which was driven by a furtive-looking wizard wearing a suit of emerald velvet."
            }
        ],
        "id": 247
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Triwizard Tournament's first task creature?",
        "answer": "Dragon",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 3222,
                "passage": "\"My bag just split ... brand-new and all ...\"\n\"Cedric,\" said Harry, \"the first task is dragons.\" \"What?\" said Cedric, looking up. \"Dragons,\" said Harry, speaking quickly, in case Professor Flitwick came out to see where Cedric had got to. \"They've got four, one for each of us, and we've got to get past them.\" Cedric stared at him. Harry saw some of the panic he'd been feeling since Saturday night flickering in Cedric's gray eyes. \"Are you sure?\" Cedric said in a hushed voice."
            }
        ],
        "id": 329
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the owner of the Hog's Head pub?",
        "answer": "Aberforth Dumbledore",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 8948,
                "passage": "\"Potter!\" Aberforth Dumbledore stood blocking the corridor ahead, his wand held ready. \"I've had hundreds of kids thundering through my pub, Potter!\" \"I know, we're evacuating,\" Harry said, \"Voldemort's -\"\n\"- attacking because they haven't handed you over, yeah,\" said Aberforth, \"I'm not deaf, the whole of Hogsmeade heard him. And it never occurred to any of you to keep a few Slytherins hostage? There are kids of Death Eaters you've just sent to safety."
            }
        ],
        "id": 148
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the magical device used to replay memories?",
        "answer": "Pensieve",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 3810,
                "passage": "\"I sometimes find, and I am sure you know the feeling, that I simply have too many thoughts and memories crammed into my mind.\" \"Er,\" said Harry, who couldn't truthfully say that he had ever felt anything of the sort. \"At these times,\" said Dumbledore, indicating the stone basin, \"I use the Pensieve. One simply siphons the excess thoughts from one's mind, pours them into the basin, and examines them at one's leisure. It becomes easier to spot patterns and links, you understand, when they are in this form.\" \"You mean ... that stuff's your thoughts?\" Harry said, staring at the swirling white substance in the basin. \"Certainly,\" said Dumbledore. \"Let me show you.\""
            }
        ],
        "id": 406
    },
    {
        "question": "In the third book, what does Harry learn about the map, and how does it aid him in the sixth book?",
        "answer": "Harry discovers a tool that reveals secrets, which later helps him track a suspicious figure.",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 1901,
                "passage": "They joined each other, they crisscrossed, they fanned into every corner of the parchment; then words began to blossom across the top, great, curly green words, that proclaimed:\nMessrs. Moony, Wormtail, Padfoot, and Prongs\nPurveyors of Aids to Magical Mischief-Makers\nare proud to present\nThe Marauder's Map\nIt was a map showing every detail of the Hogwarts castle and grounds. But the truly remarkable thing were the tiny ink dots moving around it, each labeled with a name in minuscule writing. Astounded, Harry bent over it. A labeled dot in the top left corner showed that Professor Dumbledore was pacing his study; the caretaker's cat, Mrs. Norris, was prowling the second floor; and Peeves the Poltergeist was currently bouncing around the trophy room. And as Harry's eyes traveled up and down the familiar corridors, he noticed something else. This map showed a set of passages he had never entered. And many of them seemed to lead -\n\"Right into Hogsmeade,\" said Fred, tracing one of them with his finger. \"There are seven in all. Now, Filch knows about these four\" - he pointed them out - \"but we're sure we're the only ones who know about these. Don't bother with the one behind the mirror on the fourth floor. We used it until last winter, but it's caved in - completely blocked."
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 7190,
                "passage": "Once out of sight of the entrance hall, Harry pulled the Marauder's Map and his Invisibility Cloak from his bag. Having concealed himself, he tapped the map, murmured, \"I solemnly swear that I am up to no good,\" and scanned it carefully. As it was Sunday morning, nearly all the students were inside their various common rooms, the Gryffindors in one tower, the Ravenclaws in another, the Slytherins in the dungeons, and the Hufflepuffs in the basement near the kitchens. Here and there a stray person meandered around the library or up a corridor. ... There were a few people out in the grounds ... and there, alone in the seventh-floor corridor, was Gregory Goyle. There was no sign of the Room of Requirement, but Harry was not worried about that; if Goyle was standing guard outside it, the room was open, whether the map was aware of it or not."
            }
        ],
        "id": 499
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that makes flowers appear?",
        "answer": "Orchideous",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": "3156",
                "passage": "Reference id 3156 not found"
            }
        ],
        "id": 209
    },
    {
        "question": "Which goblin agrees to help Harry break into Gringotts to find a Horcrux?",
        "answer": "Griphook assists them with the break-in.",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 8690,
                "passage": "\"I have reached my decision, Harry Potter,\" said the goblin, who was sitting cross-legged in a low chair, drumming its arms with his spindly fingers. \"Though the goblins of Gringotts will consider it base treachery, I have decided to help you -\"\n\"That's great!\" said Harry, relief surging through him. \"Griphook, thank you, we're really -\"\n\"- in return,\" said the goblin firmly, \"for payment.\" Slightly taken aback, Harry hesitated. \"How much do you want? I've got gold.\" \"Not gold,\" said Griphook. \"I have gold.\""
            }
        ],
        "id": 27
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that causes a person to be hidden?",
        "answer": "Disillusionment Charm",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 4277,
                "passage": "\"Do I have to?\" Lupin smiled but made no answer. \"Come here, boy,\" said Moody gruffly, beckoning Harry toward him with his wand. \"I need to Disillusion you.\" \"You need to what?\" said Harry nervously. \"Disillusionment Charm,\" said Moody, raising his wand. \"Lupin says you've got an Invisibility Cloak, but it won't stay on while we're flying; this'll disguise you better."
            }
        ],
        "id": 68
    },
    {
        "question": "What spell does Hermione use to repair Harry's glasses on Hogwarts Express?",
        "answer": "Reparo",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 2858,
                "passage": "...\"\nLaughing once more, Malfoy beckoned to Crabbe and Goyle, and the three of them disappeared. Ron got to his feet and slammed the sliding compartment door so hard behind them that the glass shattered. \"Ron!\" said Hermione reproachfully, and she pulled out her wand, muttered \"Reparo!\" and the glass shards flew back into a single pane and back into the door. \"Well ... making it look like he knows everything and we don't."
            }
        ],
        "id": 325
    },
    {
        "question": "In the second book, who does Harry save from the Chamber of Secrets, and how does this person assist him in the seventh book?",
        "answer": "Harry saves Ginny Weasley from the Chamber of Secrets. Ginny later becomes a key member of Dumbledore's Army and fights alongside Harry in the Battle of Hogwarts.",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 1432,
                "passage": "As Harry hurried toward her, she sat up. Her bemused eyes traveled from the huge form of the dead basilisk, over Harry, in his blood-soaked robes, then to the diary in his hand. She drew a great, shuddering gasp and tears began to pour down her face. \"Harry - oh, Harry - I tried to tell you at b-breakfast, but I c-couldn't say it in front of Percy - it was me, Harry - but I - I s-swear I d-didn't mean to - R-Riddle made me, he t-took me over - and - how did you kill that - that thing? W-where's Riddle? The last thing I r-remember is him coming out of the diary -\"\n\"It's all right,\" said Harry, holding up the diary, and showing Ginny the fang hole, \"Riddle's finished. Look! Him and the basilisk. C'mon, Ginny, let's get out of here -\"\n\"I'm going to be expelled!\" Ginny wept as Harry helped her awkwardly to her feet."
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 8956,
                "passage": "\"You can tell us what's going on.\" \"Is everyone okay?\" said Ginny and Tonks together.\n\" 'S far as we know,\" said Harry. \"Are there still people in the passage to the Hog's Head?\" He knew that the room would not be able to transform while there were still users inside it. \"I was the last to come through,\" said Mrs. Longbottom. \"I sealed it, I think it unwise to leave it open now Aberforth has left his pub. Have you seen my grandson?\""
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 8958,
                "passage": "\"He was planning to lead a group of fighters into the grounds -\"\nWithout another word, Tonks sped off. \"Ginny,\" said Harry, \"I'm sorry, but we need you to leave too. Just for a bit. Then you can come back in.\" Ginny looked simply delighted to leave her sanctuary. \"And then you can come back in!\" he shouted after her as she ran up the steps after Tonks."
            }
        ],
        "id": 413
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of Ron Weasley's youngest sister?",
        "answer": "Ginny Weasley",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 724,
                "passage": "\"There he is, Mom, there he is, look!\" It was Ginny Weasley, Ron's younger sister, but she wasn't pointing at Ron. \"Harry Potter!\" she squealed. \"Look, Mom! I can see -\"\n\"Be quiet, Ginny, and it's rude to point.\""
            }
        ],
        "id": 104
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Weasley family's owl?",
        "answer": "Errol",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": "789",
                "passage": "Reference id 789 not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "790",
                "passage": "Reference id 790 not found"
            }
        ],
        "id": 310
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that lights fires?",
        "answer": "Incendio",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 2584,
                "passage": "They glanced around as they entered and spotted Dudley. Their faces cracked into identical evil grins. \"Ah, right,\" said Mr. Weasley. \"Better get cracking then.\" He pushed up the sleeves of his robes and took out his wand. Harry saw the Dursleys draw back against the wall as one. \"Incendio!\" said Mr. Weasley, pointing his wand at the hole in the wall behind him. Flames rose at once in the fireplace, crackling merrily as though they had been burning for hours. Mr. Weasley took a small drawstring bag from his pocket, untied it, took a pinch of the powder inside, and threw it onto the flames, which turned emerald green and roared higher than ever. \"Off you go then, Fred,\" said Mr. Weasley. \"Coming,\" said Fred. \"Oh no - hang on -\"\nA bag of sweets had spilled out of Fred's pocket and the contents were now rolling in every direction - big, fat toffees in brightly colored wrappers. Fred scrambled around, cramming them back into his pocket, then gave the Dursleys a cheery wave, stepped forward, and walked right into the fire, saying \"the Burrow!\" Aunt Petunia gave a little shuddering gasp."
            }
        ],
        "id": 159
    },
    {
        "question": "Which student secretly repairs the Vanishing Cabinet that lets Death Eaters enter Hogwarts?",
        "answer": "Draco Malfoy is responsible for repairing it.",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 7458,
                "passage": "So tell me, while we wait for your friends ... how did you smuggle them in here? It seems to have taken you a long time to work out how to do it.\" Malfoy looked as though he was fighting down the urge to shout, or to vomit. He gulped and took several deep breaths, glaring at Dumbledore, his wand pointing directly at the latter's heart. Then, as though he could not help himself, he said, \"I had to mend that broken Vanishing Cabinet that no one's used for years. The one Montague got lost in last year.\" \"Aaaah.\" Dumbledore's sigh was half a groan. He closed his eyes for a moment. \"That was clever. ... There is a pair, I take it?\" \"In Borgin and Burkes,\" said Malfoy, \"and they make a kind of passage between them. Montague told me that when he was stuck in the Hogwarts one, he was trapped in limbo but sometimes he could hear what was going on at school, and sometimes what was going on in the shop, as if the cabinet was traveling between them, but he couldn't make anyone hear him."
            }
        ],
        "id": 23
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do Bill and Fleur live, providing the Trio with shelter after they escape from Malfoy Manor?",
        "answer": "They live at Shell Cottage.",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 8417,
                "passage": "said Ron with an incredulous laugh. \"Do you think I was going to go back there and tell them all I'd walked out on you? Yeah, Fred and George would've been great about it. And Ginny, she'd have been really understanding.\" \"But where have you been, then?\" asked Hermione, surprised. \"Bill and Fleur's new place. Shell Cottage. Bill's always been decent to me. He - he wasn't impressed when he heard what I'd done, but he didn't go on about it. He knew I was really sorry."
            }
        ],
        "id": 26
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the keeper of the Leaky Cauldron?",
        "answer": "Tom",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": "147",
                "passage": "Reference id 147 not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "148",
                "passage": "Reference id 148 not found"
            }
        ],
        "id": 169
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that makes objects slippery?",
        "answer": "No such spell",
        "list of reference": [],
        "id": 222
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the magical candy that makes you hiccup?",
        "answer": "Hiccough Sweets",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 2104,
                "passage": "...\"\nThey went to the post office; Ron pretended to be checking the price of an owl to Bill in Egypt so that Harry could have a good look around. The owls sat hooting softly down at him, at least three hundred of them; from Great Grays right down to tiny little Scops owls (\"Local Deliveries Only\"), which were so small they could have sat in the palm of Harry's hand. Then they visited Zonko's, which was so packed with students Harry had to exercise great care not to tread on anyone and cause a panic. There were jokes and tricks to fulfill even Fred's and George's wildest dreams; Harry gave Ron whispered orders and passed him some gold from under the cloak. They left Zonko's with their money bags considerably lighter than they had been on entering, but their pockets bulging with Dungbombs, Hiccup Sweets, Frog Spawn Soap, and a Nose-Biting Teacup apiece. The day was fine and breezy, and neither of them felt like staying indoors, so they walked past the Three Broomsticks and climbed a slope to visit the Shrieking Shack, the most haunted dwelling in Britain. It stood a little way above the rest of the village, and even in daylight was slightly creepy, with its boarded windows and dank overgrown garden. \"Even the Hogwarts ghosts avoid it,\" said Ron as they leaned on the fence, looking up at it. \"I asked Nearly Headless Nick ... he says he's heard a very rough crowd lives here. No one can get in. Fred and George tried, obviously, but all the entrances are sealed shut. ...\"\nHarry, feeling hot from their climb, was just considering taking off the cloak for a few minutes when they heard voices nearby. Someone was climbing toward the house from the other side of the hill; moments later, Malfoy had appeared, followed closely by Crabbe and Goyle. Malfoy was speaking."
            }
        ],
        "id": 197
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that lifts objects into the air upside and down?",
        "answer": "Dangling Jinx (Levicorpus)",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 6715,
                "passage": "class. On the other hand, the Prince had proved a much more effective teacher than Snape so far. Pointing his wand at nothing in particular, he gave it an upward flick and said Levicorpus! inside his head. \"Aaaaaaaargh!\" There was a flash of light and the room was full of voices: Everyone had woken up as Ron had let out a yell. Harry sent Advanced Potion-Making flying in panic; Ron was dangling upside down in midair as though an invisible hook had hoisted him up by the ankle."
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 7037,
                "passage": "Staggering, he looked around. Ron's fist was drawn right back; his face was contorted with rage; he was about to strike again. Harry reacted instinctively; his wand was out of his pocket and the incantation sprang to mind without conscious thought: Levicorpus! Ron yelled as his heel was wrenched upward once more; he dangled helplessly, upside down, his robes hanging off him. \"What was that for?\" Harry bellowed. \"You insulted her, Harry! You said it was a joke!\" shouted Ron, who was slowly turning purple in the face as all the blood rushed to his head. \"This is insane!\" said Harry. \"What's got into - ?\" And then he saw the box lying open on Ron's bed, and the truth hit him with the force of a stampeding troll. \"Where did you get those Chocolate Cauldrons?\" \"They were a birthday present!\""
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 8765,
                "passage": "snarled the goblin. \"Then what do we do?\" said Harry, glaring at the goblin. \"If you want the sword, Griphook, then you'll have to help us more than - wait! Can I touch stuff with the sword? Hermione, give it here!\" Hermione fumbled inside her robes, drew out the beaded bag, rummaged for a few seconds, then removed the shining sword. Harry seized it by its rubied hilt and touched the tip of the blade to a silver flagon nearby, which did not multiply. \"If I can just poke the sword through a handle - but how am I going to get up there?\" The shelf on which the cup reposed was out of reach for any of them, even Ron, who was tallest. The heat from the enchanted treasure rose in waves, and sweat ran down Harry's face and back as he struggled to think of a way up to the cup; and then he heard the dragon roar on the other side of the vault door, and the sound of clanking growing louder and louder. They were truly trapped now: There was no way out except through the door, and a horde of goblins seemed to be approaching on the other side. Harry looked at Ron and Hermione and saw terror in their faces. \"Hermione,\" said Harry as the clanking grew louder, \"I've got to get up there, we've got to get rid of it -\"\nShe raised her wand, pointed it at Harry, and whispered, \"Levicorpus.\" Hoisted into the air by his ankle, Harry hit a suit of armor and replicas burst out of it like white-hot bodies, filling the cramped space. With screams of pain Ron, Hermione, and the two goblins were knocked aside into other objects, which also began to replicate."
            }
        ],
        "id": 177
    },
    {
        "question": "What magical creature does Harry ride to escape in the seventh book, and does the Ukrainian Ironbelly dragon appear in the first task of the Triwizard Tourament in the fourth book?",
        "answer": "Harry escapes Gringotts by riding a gigantic dragon and Ukrainian Ironbelly dragon does not appear in the first task of the Triwizard Tournament.",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 8787,
                "passage": "\"We'll go to Hogsmeade,\" said Harry, \"and try to work something out once we see what the protection around the school's like. Get under the Cloak, Hermione, I want to stick together this time.\" \"But we don't really fit -\"\n\"It'll be dark, no one's going to notice our feet.\" The flapping of enormous wings echoed across the black water: The dragon had drunk its fill and risen into the air. They paused in their preparations to watch it climb higher and higher, now black against the rapidly darkening sky, until it vanished over a nearby mountain. Then Hermione walked forward and took her place between the other two. Harry pulled the Cloak down as far as it would go, and together they turned on the spot into the crushing darkness."
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 3247,
                "passage": "\"Ladies first,\" he said, offering it to Fleur Delacour. She put a shaking hand inside the bag and drew out a tiny, perfect model of a dragon - a Welsh Green. It had the number two around its neck. And Harry knew, by the fact that Fleur showed no sign of surprise, but rather a determined resignation, that he had been right: Madame Maxime had told her what was coming. The same held true for Krum. He pulled out the scarlet Chinese Fireball."
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 3248,
                "passage": "It had a number three around its neck. He didn't even blink, just sat back down and stared at the ground. Cedric put his hand into the bag, and out came the blueish-gray Swedish Short-Snout, the number one tied around its neck. Knowing what was left, Harry put his hand into the silk bag and pulled out the Hungarian Horntail, and the number four. It stretched its wings as he looked down at it, and bared its minuscule fangs. \"Well, there you are!\" said Bagman. \"You have each pulled out the dragon you will face, and the numbers refer to the order in which you are to take on the dragons, do you see? Now, I'm going to have to leave you in a moment, because I'm commentating."
            }
        ],
        "id": 423
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that causes a person to grow?",
        "answer": "Engorgio",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 2955,
                "passage": "Moody was looking very intently at Neville, this time with both eyes. \"Your name's Longbottom?\" he said, his magical eye swooping down to check the register again. Neville nodded nervously, but Moody made no further inquiries. Turning back to the class at large, he reached into the jar for the next spider and placed it upon the desktop, where it remained motionless, apparently too scared to move. \"The Cruciatus Curse,\" said Moody. \"Needs to be a bit bigger for you to get the idea,\" he said, pointing his wand at the spider. \"Engorgio!\" The spider swelled. It was now larger than a tarantula. Abandoning all pretense, Ron pushed his chair backward, as far away from Moody's desk as possible. Moody raised his wand again, pointed it at the spider, and muttered, \"Crucio!\" At once, the spider's legs bent in upon its body; it rolled over and began to twitch horribly, rocking from side to side."
            }
        ],
        "id": 95
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the head of Slytherin house?",
        "answer": "Severus Snape",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 299,
                "passage": "Lots of people had come from Muggle families and, like him, hadn't had any idea that they were witches and wizards. There was so much to learn that even people like Ron didn't have much of a head start. Friday was an important day for Harry and Ron. They finally managed to find their way down to the Great Hall for breakfast without getting lost once. \"What have we got today?\" Harry asked Ron as he poured sugar on his porridge. \"Double Potions with the Slytherins,\" said Ron. \"Snape's Head of Slytherin House. They say he always favors them - we'll be able to see if it's true.\" \"Wish McGonagall favored us,\" said Harry. Professor McGonagall was head of Gryffindor House, but it hadn't stopped her from giving them a huge pile of homework the day before. Just then, the mail arrived."
            }
        ],
        "id": 124
    },
    {
        "question": "What creature does Harry ride in the lake during the second task?",
        "answer": "A giant squid (implied help)",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": "B",
                "passage": "Reference id B not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "o",
                "passage": "Reference id o not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "o",
                "passage": "Reference id o not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "k",
                "passage": "Reference id k not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": " ",
                "passage": "Reference id   not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "4",
                "passage": "Reference id 4 not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": ",",
                "passage": "Reference id , not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": " ",
                "passage": "Reference id   not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "C",
                "passage": "Reference id C not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "h",
                "passage": "Reference id h not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "a",
                "passage": "Reference id a not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "p",
                "passage": "Reference id p not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "t",
                "passage": "Reference id t not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "e",
                "passage": "Reference id e not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "r",
                "passage": "Reference id r not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": " ",
                "passage": "Reference id   not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "2",
                "passage": "Reference id 2 not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "6",
                "passage": "Reference id 6 not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": ",",
                "passage": "Reference id , not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": " ",
                "passage": "Reference id   not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "P",
                "passage": "Reference id P not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "a",
                "passage": "Reference id a not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "r",
                "passage": "Reference id r not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "a",
                "passage": "Reference id a not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "g",
                "passage": "Reference id g not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "r",
                "passage": "Reference id r not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "a",
                "passage": "Reference id a not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "p",
                "passage": "Reference id p not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "h",
                "passage": "Reference id h not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": " ",
                "passage": "Reference id   not found"
            },
            {
                "ref_id": "6",
                "passage": "Reference id 6 not found"
            }
        ],
        "id": 170
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that disarms an opponent?",
        "answer": "Expelliarmus",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": "1138",
                "passage": "Reference id 1138 not found"
            }
        ],
        "id": 51
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that makes flowers appear?",
        "answer": "Orchideous",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 3156,
                "passage": "\"Yes,\" said Mr. Ollivander, \"yes, I've never used veela hair myself, of course. I find it makes for rather temperamental wands ... however, to each his own, and if this suits you ...\"\nMr. Ollivander ran his fingers along the wand, apparently checking for scratches or bumps; then he muttered, \"Orchideous!\" and a bunch of flowers burst from the wand tip. \"Very well, very well, it's in fine working order,\" said Mr. Ollivander, scooping up the flowers and handing them to Fleur with her wand. \"Mr. Diggory, you next.\" Fleur glided back to her seat, smiling at Cedric as he passed her. \"Ah, now, this is one of mine, isn't it?\" said Mr. Ollivander, with much more enthusiasm, as Cedric handed over his wand. \"Yes, I remember it well. Containing a single hair from the tail of a particularly fine male unicorn ... must have been seventeen hands; nearly gored me with his horn after I plucked his tail. Twelve and a quarter inches ... ash ... pleasantly springy. It's in fine condition."
            }
        ],
        "id": 209
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the matron of Hogwarts infirmary?",
        "answer": "Madam Pomfrey",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 6547,
                "passage": "\"Draco Malfoy,\" said Harry bitterly. \"Thanks for ... well ...\"\n\"No problem,\" said Tonks, without smiling. From what Harry could see in the darkness, she was as mousy-haired and miserable-looking as she had been when he had met her at the Burrow. \"I can fix your nose if you stand still.\" Harry did not think much of this idea; he had been intending to visit Madam Pomfrey, the matron, in whom he had a little more confidence when it came to Healing Spells, but it seemed rude to say this, so he stayed stock-still and closed his eyes. \"Episkey,\" said Tonks. Harry's nose felt very hot, and then very cold. He raised a hand and felt it gingerly. It seemed to be mended."
            }
        ],
        "id": 385
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the village where Harry's parents lived?",
        "answer": "Godric's Hollow",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 27,
                "passage": "\"What they're saying,\" she pressed on, \"is that last night Voldemort turned up in Godric's Hollow. He went to find the Potters. The rumor is that Lily and James Potter are - are - that they're - dead.\" Dumbledore bowed his head. Professor McGonagall gasped. \"Lily and James ... I can't believe it ... I didn't want to believe it ... Oh, Albus ...\"\nDumbledore reached out and patted her on the shoulder. \"I know ... I know ...\" he said heavily. Professor McGonagall's voice trembled as she went on. \"That's not all."
            }
        ],
        "id": 134
    },
    {
        "question": "What does Harry find in the potion in the sixth book, and how does it relate to the second book?",
        "answer": "Harry excels with a recipe from a hidden source, tying back to an earlier encounter with a deceptive book.",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 6620,
                "passage": "To his astonishment, it immediately exuded so much juice he was amazed the shriveled bean could have held it all. Hastily scooping it all into the cauldron he saw, to his surprise, that the potion immediately turned exactly the shade of lilac described by the textbook. His annoyance with the previous owner vanishing on the spot, Harry now squinted at the next line of instructions. According to the book, he had to stir counterclockwise until the potion turned clear as water. According to the addition the previous owner had made, however, he ought to add a clockwise stir after every seventh counterclockwise stir. Could the old owner be right twice? Harry stirred counterclockwise, held his breath, and stirred once clockwise. The effect was immediate. The potion turned palest pink. \"How are you doing that?\" demanded Hermione, who was red-faced and whose hair was growing bushier and bushier in the fumes from her cauldron; her potion was still resolutely purple. \"Add a clockwise stir -\"\n\"No, no, the book says counterclockwise!\" she snapped. Harry shrugged and continued what he was doing. Seven stirs counterclockwise, one clockwise, pause ... seven stirs counterclockwise, one stir clockwise ...\nAcross the table, Ron was cursing fluently under his breath; his potion looked like liquid licorice. Harry glanced around. As far as he could see, no one else's potion had turned as pale as his. He felt elated, something that had certainly never happened before in this dungeon. \"And time's ..."
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 1396,
                "passage": "Little Ginny's been writing in it for months and months, telling me all her pitiful worries and woes - how her brothers tease her, how she had to come to school with secondhand robes and books, how\" - Riddle's eyes glinted - \"how she didn't think famous, good, great Harry Potter would ever like her. ...\"\nAll the time he spoke, Riddle's eyes never left Harry's face. There was an almost hungry look in them. \"It's very boring, having to listen to the silly little troubles of an eleven-year-old girl,\" he went on. \"But I was patient. I wrote back."
            }
        ],
        "id": 500
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the candy that makes your tongue grow?",
        "answer": "Ton-Tongue Toffee",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 2591,
                "passage": "Harry spun faster and faster, elbows tucked tightly to his sides, blurred fireplaces flashing past him, until he started to feel sick and closed his eyes. Then, when at last he felt himself slowing down, he threw out his hands and came to a halt in time to prevent himself from falling face forward out of the Weasleys' kitchen fire. \"Did he eat it?\" said Fred excitedly, holding out a hand to pull Harry to his feet. \"Yeah,\" said Harry, straightening up. \"What was it?\" \"Ton-Tongue Toffee,\" said Fred brightly. \"George and I invented them, and we've been looking for someone to test them on all summer. ...\"\nThe tiny kitchen exploded with laughter; Harry looked around and saw that Ron and George were sitting at the scrubbed wooden table with two red-haired people Harry had never seen before, though he knew immediately who they must be: Bill and Charlie, the two eldest Weasley brothers."
            }
        ],
        "id": 139
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the first Weasley sibling Harry meets?",
        "answer": "Ron Weasley",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 234,
                "passage": "Harry looked at Ron, and was relieved to see by his stunned face that he hadn't learned all the course books by heart either. \"I'm Ron Weasley,\" Ron muttered. \"Harry Potter,\" said Harry. \"Are you really?\" said Hermione. \"I know all about you, of course - I got a few extra books for background reading, and you're in Modern Magical History and The Rise and Fall of the Dark Arts and Great Wizarding Events of the Twentieth Century.\" \"Am I?\" said Harry, feeling dazed."
            }
        ],
        "id": 151
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the magical creature that live in water?",
        "answer": "Kappa",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 1787,
                "passage": "In no time at all, Defense Against the Dark Arts had become most people's favorite class. Only Draco Malfoy and his gang of Slytherins had anything bad to say about Professor Lupin. \"Look at the state of his robes,\" Malfoy would say in a loud whisper as Professor Lupin passed. \"He dresses like our old house-elf.\" But no one else cared that Professor Lupin's robes were patched and frayed. His next few lessons were just as interesting as the first. After boggarts, they studied Red Caps, nasty little goblinlike creatures that lurked wherever there had been bloodshed: in the dungeons of castles and the potholes of deserted battlefields, waiting to bludgeon those who had gotten lost. From Red Caps they moved on to kappas, creepy water-dwellers that looked like scaly monkeys, with webbed hands itching to strangle unwitting waders in their ponds. Harry only wished he was as happy with some of his other classes."
            }
        ],
        "id": 231
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the headmaster of Hogwarts before Dumbledore?",
        "answer": "Armando Dippet",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 5241,
                "passage": "cried a frail-looking old wizard whom Harry recognized as Dumbledore's predecessor, Armando Dippet. \"Shame on you, Phineas!\" \"Shall I persuade him, Dumbledore?\" called a gimlet-eyed witch, raising an unusually thick wand that looked not unlike a birch rod. \"Oh, very well,\" said the wizard called Phineas, eyeing this wand slightly apprehensively, \"though he may well have destroyed my picture by now, he's done most of the family -\"\n\"Sirius knows not to destroy your portrait,\" said Dumbledore, and Harry realized immediately where he had heard Phineas's voice before: issuing from the apparently empty frame in his bedroom in Grimmauld Place. \"You are to give him the message that Arthur Weasley has been gravely injured and that his wife, children, and Harry Potter will be arriving at his house shortly. Do you understand?\" \"Arthur Weasley, injured, wife and children and Harry Potter coming to stay,\" recited Phineas in a bored voice. \"Yes, yes ... very well. ...\"\nHe sloped away into the frame of the portrait and disappeared from view at the very moment that the study door opened again. Fred, George, and Ginny were ushered inside by Professor McGonagall, all three of them looking disheveled and shocked, still in their night things. \"Harry - what's going on?\" asked Ginny, who looked frightened. \"Professor McGonagall says you saw Dad hurt -\"\n\"Your father has been injured in the course of his work for the Order of the Phoenix,\" said Dumbledore before Harry could speak. \"He has been taken to St. Mungo's Hospital for Magical Maladies and Injuries. I am sending you back to Sirius's house, which is much more convenient for the hospital than the Burrow."
            }
        ],
        "id": 343
    },
    {
        "question": "What creature does Harry fight in the Chamber of Secrets?",
        "answer": "A Basilisk",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 1340,
                "passage": "Harry smoothed it out eagerly and Ron leaned close to read it, too. Of the many fearsome beasts and monsters that roam our land, there is none more curious or more deadly than the Basilisk, known also as the King of Serpents. This snake, which may reach gigantic size and live many hundreds of years, is born from a chicken's egg, hatched beneath a toad. Its methods of killing are most wondrous, for aside from its deadly and venomous fangs, the Basilisk has a murderous stare, and all who are fixed with the beam of its eye shall suffer instant death. Spiders flee before the Basilisk, for it is their mortal enemy, and the Basilisk flees only from the crowing of the rooster, which is fatal to it. And beneath this, a single word had been written, in a hand Harry recognized as Hermione's. Pipes. It was as though somebody had just flicked a light on in his brain. \"Ron,\" he breathed. \"This is it. This is the answer."
            }
        ],
        "id": 106
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Slytherin boy who loves potions?",
        "answer": "Severus Snape",
        "list of reference": [],
        "id": 229
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that reveals hidden messages?",
        "answer": "Aparecium",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": "1230",
                "passage": "Reference id 1230 not found"
            }
        ],
        "id": 89
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the magical plant that bites?",
        "answer": "Fanged Geranium",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 5841,
                "passage": "There was no time to relax that night - they went straight to the common room after dinner and submerged themselves in studying for Transfiguration next day. Harry went to bed, his head buzzing with complex spell models and theories. He forgot the definition of a Switching Spell during his written exam next morning, but thought his practical could have been a lot worse. At least he managed to vanish the whole of his iguana, whereas poor Hannah Abbott lost her head completely at the next table and somehow managed to multiply her ferret into a flock of flamingos, causing the examination to be halted for ten minutes while the birds were captured and carried out of the Hall. They had their Herbology exam on Wednesday (other than a small bite from a Fanged Geranium, Harry felt he had done reasonably well) and then, on Thursday, Defense Against the Dark Arts. Here, for the first time, Harry felt sure he had passed. He had no problem with any of the written questions and took particular pleasure, during the practical examination, in performing all the counterjinxes and defensive spells right in front of Umbridge, who was watching coolly from near the doors into the entrance hall. \"Oh bravo!\" cried Professor Tofty, who was examining Harry again, when Harry demonstrated a perfect boggart banishing spell. \"Very good indeed! Well, I think that's all, Potter ... unless ...\"\nHe leaned forward a little."
            }
        ],
        "id": 245
    },
    {
        "question": "In Half-Blood Prince, students learn about the complexities of Apparition. What are the three “D's” they must remember when Apparating, and how do these principles symbolize the series' broader themes of control and determination?",
        "answer": "The three D's that students must remember when learning to Apparate are Destination, Determination, and Deliberation.",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 7021,
                "passage": "\"Splinching, or the separation of random body parts,\" said Wilkie Twycross dispassionately, \"occurs when the mind is insufficiently determined. You must concentrate continuously upon your destination, and move, without haste, but with deliberation ... thus.\" Twycross stepped forward, turned gracefully on the spot with his arms outstretched, and vanished in a swirl of robes, reappearing at the back of the Hall. \"Remember the three D's,\" he said, \"and try again ... one - two - three -\"\nBut an hour later, Susan's Splinching was still the most interesting thing that had happened. Twycross did not seem discouraged."
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 7017,
                "passage": "\"Destination, Determination, Deliberation! \"Step one: Fix your mind firmly upon the desired destination,\" said Twycross. \"In this case, the interior of your hoop. Kindly concentrate upon that destination now.\" Everybody looked around furtively to check that everyone else was staring into their hoop, then hastily did as they were told. Harry gazed at the circular patch of dusty floor enclosed by his hoop and tried hard to think of nothing else. This proved impossible, as he couldn't stop puzzling over what Malfoy was doing that needed lookouts. \"Step two,\" said Twycross, \"focus your determination to occupy the visualized space! Let your yearning to enter it flood from your mind to every particle of your body!\" Harry glanced around surreptitiously. A little way to his left, Ernie Macmillan was contemplating his hoop so hard that his face had turned pink; it looked as though he was straining to lay a Quaffle-sized egg. Harry bit back a laugh and hastily returned his gaze to his own hoop."
            }
        ],
        "id": 615
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Death Eater who impersonates Moody?",
        "answer": "Barty Crouch",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 3993,
                "passage": "But I think, in the excitement of tonight, our fake Moody might have forgotten to take it as frequently as he should have done ... on the hour ... every hour. ... We shall see.\" Dumbledore pulled out the chair at the desk and sat down upon it, his eyes fixed upon the unconscious Moody on the floor. Harry stared at him too. Minutes passed in silence."
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 3994,
                "passage": "...\nThen, before Harry's very eyes, the face of the man on the floor began to change. The scars were disappearing, the skin was becoming smooth; the mangled nose became whole and started to shrink. The long mane of grizzled gray hair was withdrawing into the scalp and turning the color of straw. Suddenly, with a loud clunk, the wooden leg fell away as a normal leg regrew in its place; next moment, the magical eyeball had popped out of the man's face as a real eye replaced it; it rolled away across the floor and continued to swivel in every direction. Harry saw a man lying before him, pale-skinned, slightly freckled, with a mop of fair hair. He knew who he was. He had seen him in Dumbledore's Pensieve, had watched him being led away from court by the dementors, trying to convince Mr. Crouch that he was innocent ... but he was lined around the eyes now and looked much older. ..."
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 3995,
                "passage": "There were hurried footsteps outside in the corridor. Snape had returned with Winky at his heels. Professor McGonagall was right behind them. \"Crouch!\" Snape said, stopping dead in the doorway. \"Barty Crouch!\" \"Good heavens,\" said Professor McGonagall, stopping dead and staring down at the man on the floor. Filthy, disheveled, Winky peered around Snape's legs. Her mouth opened wide and she let out a piercing shriek. \"Master Barty, Master Barty, what is you doing here?\" She flung herself forward onto the young man's chest. \"You is killed him! You is killed him! You is killed Master's son!\" \"He is simply Stunned, Winky,\" said Dumbledore."
            }
        ],
        "id": 355
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Weasley family's owl?",
        "answer": "Errol",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 789,
                "passage": "\"I'm glad we came to get you, anyway,\" said Ron. \"I was getting really worried when you didn't answer any of my letters. I thought it was Errol's fault at first -\"\n\"Who's Errol?\" \"Our owl. He's ancient. It wouldn't be the first time he'd collapsed on a delivery. So then I tried to borrow Hermes -\"\n\"Who?\""
            },
            {
                "ref_id": 790,
                "passage": "\"The owl Mum and Dad bought Percy when he was made prefect,\" said Fred from the front. \"But Percy wouldn't lend him to me,\" said Ron. \"Said he needed him.\" \"Percy's been acting very oddly this summer,\" said George, frowning. \"And he has been sending a lot of letters and spending a load of time shut up in his room. ... I mean, there's only so many times you can polish a prefect badge. ... You're driving too far west, Fred,\" he added, pointing at a compass on the dashboard. Fred twiddled the steering wheel."
            }
        ],
        "id": 310
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of Voldemort's snake?",
        "answer": "Nagini",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 2518,
                "passage": "\"Nagini has interesting news, Wormtail,\" it said. \"In-indeed, My Lord?\" said Wormtail. \"Indeed, yes,\" said the voice. \"According to Nagini, there is an old Muggle standing right outside this room, listening to every word we say.\" Frank didn't have a chance to hide himself. There were footsteps, and then the door of the room was flung wide open. A short, balding man with graying hair, a pointed nose, and small, watery eyes stood before Frank, a mixture of fear and alarm in his face. \"Invite him inside, Wormtail. Where are your manners?\" The cold voice was coming from the ancient armchair before the fire, but Frank couldn't see the speaker. The snake, on the other hand, was curled up on the rotting hearth rug, like some horrible travesty of a pet dog. Wormtail beckoned Frank into the room."
            }
        ],
        "id": 313
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of Dumbledore's phoenix?",
        "answer": "Fawkes",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 1176,
                "passage": "Standing on a golden perch behind the door was a decrepit-looking bird that resembled a half-plucked turkey. Harry stared at it and the bird looked balefully back, making its gagging noise again. Harry thought it looked very ill. Its eyes were dull and, even as Harry watched, a couple more feathers fell out of its tail. Harry was just thinking that all he needed was for Dumbledore's pet bird to die while he was alone in the office with it, when the bird burst into flames. Harry yelled in shock and backed away into the desk. He looked feverishly around in case there was a glass of water somewhere but couldn't see one; the bird, meanwhile, had become a fireball; it gave one loud shriek and next second there was nothing but a smoldering pile of ash on the floor. The office door opened. Dumbledore came in, looking very somber. \"Professor,\" Harry gasped. \"Your bird - I couldn't do anything - he just caught fire -\"\nTo Harry's astonishment, Dumbledore smiled. \"About time, too,\" he said. \"He's been looking dreadful for days; I've been telling him to get a move on.\" He chuckled at the stunned look on Harry's face. \"Fawkes is a phoenix, Harry."
            }
        ],
        "id": 332
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Slytherin Quidditch captain in Harry's sixth year?",
        "answer": "Urquhart",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 6833,
                "passage": "\"Captains shake hands,\" she said, and Harry had his hand crushed by the new Slytherin Captain, Urquhart. \"Mount your brooms. On the whistle ... three ... two ... one ...\"\nThe whistle sounded, Harry and the others kicked off hard from the frozen ground, and they were away. Harry soared around the perimeter of the grounds, looking around for the Snitch and keeping one eye on Harper, who was zigzagging far below him. Then a voice that was jarringly different to the usual commentator's started up."
            }
        ],
        "id": 389
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that makes objects stick together?",
        "answer": "Sticking Charm",
        "list of reference": [
            {
                "ref_id": 4413,
                "passage": "\"Master always liked his little joke,\" said Kreacher, bowing again, and continuing in an undertone, \"Master was a nasty ungrateful swine who broke his mother's heart -\"\n\"My mother didn't have a heart, Kreacher,\" Sirius snapped. \"She kept herself alive out of pure spite.\" Kreacher bowed again and said, \"Whatever Master says,\" then muttered furiously, \"Master is not fit to wipe slime from his mother's boots, oh my poor Mistress, what would she say if she saw Kreacher serving him, how she hated him, what a disappointment he was -\"\n\"I asked you what you were up to,\" said Sirius coldly. \"Every time you show up pretending to be cleaning, you sneak something off to your room so we can't throw it out.\" \"Kreacher would never move anything from its proper place in Master's house,\" said the elf, then muttered very fast, \"Mistress would never forgive Kreacher if the tapestry was thrown out, seven centuries it's been in the family, Kreacher must save it, Kreacher will not let Master and the blood traitors and the brats destroy it -\"\n\"I thought it might be that,\" said Sirius, casting a disdainful look at the opposite wall. \"She'll have put another Permanent Sticking Charm on the back of it, I don't doubt, but if I can get rid of it I certainly will. Now go away, Kreacher.\" It seemed that Kreacher did not dare disobey a direct order; nevertheless, the look he gave Sirius as he shuffled out past him was redolent of deepest loathing and he muttered all the way out of the room. \"- comes back from Azkaban ordering Kreacher around, oh my poor Mistress, what would she say if she saw the house now, scum living in it, her treasures thrown out, she swore he was no son of hers and he's back, they say he's a murderer too -\"\n\"Keep muttering and I will be a murderer!\" said Sirius irritably, and he slammed the door shut on the elf. \"Sirius, he's not right in the head,\" said Hermione pleadingly, \"I don't think he realizes we can hear him.\" \"He's been alone too long,\" said Sirius, \"taking mad orders from my mother's portrait and talking to himself, but he was always a foul little -\"\n\"If you just set him free,\" said Hermione hopefully, \"maybe -\"\n\"We can't set him free, he knows too much about the Order,\" said Sirius curtly. \"And anyway, the shock would kill him. You suggest to him that he leaves this house, see how he takes it.\""
            }
        ],
        "id": 201
    }
]